Guide to the Dunlap family papers, 1733-1984
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Dunlap family papers 1733-1984
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Dunlap family.
3.2 Linear Feet 741 Items
Family with members in both Ripon, Wis., and Ann Arbor, Mich.
Collection contains letters and photocopies of letters between family members, naturalization papers; a poem by Helen E. (Richley) Healy; copies of an undated memoir by Gertrude (Clark) Dunlap; an undated chronicle of the early years of James E. Dunlap; several other memoirs, journals and diaries; descriptions of a voyage in an American clipper ship; Civil War letters; genealogies of various families including the Dunlap, Dunlop, Life, Clark, Cooke, and Delamere families; original photographs; and a land deed. The 2007 addition (2007-0168) (600 items; 2.5 lin. ft.; dated 1821-1910 and undated) contains genealogies and family histories of the Dunlap and Life families and biographies of the family members; diaries dated 1865, 1867, 1873-1898, and 1910; autograph books; letters and a scrapbook from the Civil War; daguerreotypes and ambrotypes; and a bayonet presumably from the Civil War. Also included are transcripts of several of the letters and diaries.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Dunlap family papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1984, 1988, 2007.
Biographical Note
Family with members in both Ripon, Wis., and Ann Arbor, Mich.
Collection Overview
Collection contains letters and photocopies of letters between family members, naturalization papers; a poem by Helen E. (Richley) Healy; copies of an undated memoir by Gertrude (Clark) Dunlap; an undated chronicle of the early years of James E. Dunlap; several other memoirs, journals and diaries; descriptions of a voyage in an American clipper ship; Civil War letters; genealogies of various families including the Dunlap, Dunlop, Life, Clark, Cooke, and Delamere families; original photographs; and a land deed.
The 2007 addition (2007-0168) (600 items; 2.5 lin. ft.; dated 1821-1910 and undated) contains genealogies and family histories of the Dunlap and Life families and biographies of the family members; diaries dated 1865, 1867, 1873-1898, and 1910; autograph books; letters and a scrapbook from the Civil War; daguerreotypes and ambrotypes; and a bayonet presumably from the Civil War. Also included are transcripts of several of the letters and diaries.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Dunlap family
Life family
Clark family
Cooke family
Delamere family
Dunlap, James E. (James Eugene), b. 1889
Dunlap, Augustus Eugene
Dunlap, Gertrude Clark
Healy, Helen E. Richley
Soldiers -- Wisconsin -- Correspondence
United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives
Wisconsin -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives
Ambrotypes
Daguerreotypes
Diaries
Genealogies
Contents of Collection
- Accessions 1984 and 1988, 1733-1984, 1 Box and 1 Folder
  Accessions 1984 and 1988 contain letters and photocopies of letters between family members, naturalization papers; a poem by Helen E. (Richley) Healy; copies of an undated memoir by Gertrude (Clark) Dunlap; an undated chronicle of the early years of James E. Dunlap; several other memoirs, journals and diaries; descriptions of a voyage in an American clipper ship; Civil War letters; genealogies of various families including the Dunlap, Dunlop, Life, Clark, Cooke, and Delamere families; original photographs; and a land deed.
  - Correspondence, 1824-1972 (Box 1)
  - Diary of Augustus Eugene Dunlap, 1865
  - Account book Augustus Eugene Dunlap, 1865-1971
  - Legal papers, 1845-1856
  - Addresses and Writings, 1918-1996
  - Journal of Andrew Edwards, Jr., 1821
  - Reminiscences of Grandmother Life by Gertrude (Clark) Dunlap
  - Notes on Sutterlee Clark
  - Genealogy
  - Pictures
  - Genealogies, 1948, 1984, (photocopy)
  - Memoir, 1957, (photocopy) (Box 2)
- Addition 2007 (2007-0168), 3 Boxes
  Addition (600 items; 2.5 lin. ft.; dated 1821-1910 and undated) contains family histories of the Dunlap and Life families and biographies of the family members; diaries dated 1865, 1867, 1873-1898, and 1910; autograph books; letters from the Civil War; genealogies; a scrapbook from the Civil War; daguerreotypes and ambrotypes; and a bayonet presumably from the Civil War. Also included are transcripts of several of the letters and diaries.
  - Photocopy of sea diary, original dated 1921 (Box 2)
  - A History of Salem Witch Trials
  - Photograph copies of family histories and letters
  - Genealogies
  - Other histories related to the Dunlap family
  - Deeds
  - Transcript of A.E. Dunlap's Civil War diary
  - A Soldier's Friend, Civil War companion book
  - History of Morrill, Maine.
  - Photocopies of the Life family history
  - Biography of James E. Dunlap
  - Belt Buckle, US (Box 3)
  - Civil War medal
  - James Dunlap Civil War correspondence, 1860s
  - Autograph books, 1800s
  - Plaque (diploma?)
  - Civil War scrapbook
  - Diaries, 1865; 1867; 1873-1898; 1910, and account books, (38 items) (Box 4)
  - Ambrotypes and daguerreotypes, (9 photographs) (Box 5)
  - Bayonet (Box 6)